<dashboard>
    <label>Scatterplot Matrix</label>
    <row>
        <panel>
            <html>
                <h1>Scatterplot Matrix</h1>
                <blockquote>
                    The scatterplot matrix visualization allows comparison between numeric sets of data, giving a rough
                    idea if there is a linear correlation between multiple fields. The scatterplot matrix consists of
                    Rows and Columns of individual Scatterplots that plot an X and a Y value. These values come from the
                    fields sent from the search bar.
                </blockquote>
                <h2>How To Use and Read the Scatterplot Matrix</h2>
                <blockquote>
                    The scatterplot matrix could be considered a table of sorts. Each row compares data against the
                    column. So for each label (or field) that is displayed, follow the label to the scatterplot, and
                    that is what is being compared. For example, the top right box of the example on this dashboard
                    compares avg_kbps (Y axis) to stdevp_kbps (X axis). The bottom left box compares avg_kbps (X axis)
                    to stdevp_kbps (Y axis). The axis are switched, and give a different visualization of the data.
                </blockquote>
                <blockquote>
                    Additionally, the graph supports some interactivity. Click and drag over a portion of a scatterplot,
                    and the same XY coordinates in the other plots will also be highlighted, and the legend will reflect
                    the items within that highlight. Mouseover the legend items, and the corresponding data points will
                    be highlighted in the scatter plots.
                </blockquote>
                <blockquote>
                    You can find more information for Scatterplot Matricies at the links below.
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            <a href="https://learningomics.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/scatterplot-matrices/"
                               target="_blank">Learning Omics
                            </a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a href="http://www.itl.nist.gov/div898/handbook/eda/section3/eda33qb.htm" target="_blank">
                                Engineering Statistics Handbook
                            </a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </blockquote>
                <h2>Configuration Options</h2>
                <blockquote>Scatterplot Matrix has many different configuration options, each split into similar
                    sections. The options are displayed like this:
                    <ul>
                        <li>Configuration Option Name</li>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Valid Setting Options</li>
                            <li>Description</li>
                        </ul>
                    </ul>
                </blockquote>
            </html>
        </panel>
        <panel ref="Aplura_Viz_-_Scatterplot_Matrix" app="Splunk_TA_common-viz"></panel>
    </row>
    <row>
        <panel>
            <html>
                <h1>Configuration Options</h1>
                <div style="width:24%;display:inline-block;vertical-align:text-top;">
                    <h3>Graph</h3>
                    <blockquote>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Box Padding
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This controls the space around each scatterplot.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Box Size
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This controls the size of each scatterplot.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Number of Ticks
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This controls the number of tick marks on each axis.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Axis Label Offset
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This controls how far away from the scatterplot matrix the labels for the axis
                                        appear.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Height
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This is the height of the SVG. If you have clipping due to size, increase
                                        this.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Width
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This is the width of the SVG. If you have clipping due to size, increase this.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </blockquote>
                </div>
                <div style="width:24%;display:inline-block;vertical-align:text-top;">
                    <h3>Legend</h3>
                    <blockquote>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Show Legend
                                <ul>
                                    <li>Yes, No</li>
                                    <li>This toggles the Legend.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Height (px)
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This is the height of the Legend Text.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Position
                                <ul>
                                    <li>Left, Right</li>
                                    <li>This controls where the legend is placed, either to the left or right of the
                                        matrix.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Top Offset
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This controls how far from the top of the Visualization the legend will
                                        display.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Left Offset
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>THis controls how far from the left of the Visualization the legend will
                                        display.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </blockquote>
                </div>
                <div style="width:24%;display:inline-block;vertical-align:text-top;">
                    <h3>Trendline</h3>
                    <blockquote>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Show Trendlines
                                <ul>
                                    <li>Yes, No</li>
                                    <li>This toggles the trendlines for each scatterplot.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Show R-Value
                                <ul>
                                    <li>No, R, R²</li>
                                    <li>Controls if, and how, the R value is displayed on the graph.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Show One-to-One Data
                                <ul>
                                    <li>Yes, No</li>
                                    <li>This controls the scatterplots on the Top-left to Bottom-Right Diagonal. This
                                        will remove the data points for those plots if No.
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Trendline Width
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This sets the width of the Trendline.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li>Trendline Color
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;hex color&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This sets the color of the Trendline.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </blockquote>
                </div>
                <div style="width:24%;display:inline-block;vertical-align:text-top;">
                    <h3>Debug</h3>
                    <blockquote>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Javascript Logging
                                <ul>
                                    <li>Yes, No</li>
                                    <li>Disables or enables the logging of debug information for the visualization.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </blockquote>
                    <h3>Data Points</h3>
                    <blockquote>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Dot Size
                                <ul>
                                    <li>&lt;integer&gt;</li>
                                    <li>This controls the size of the data points in the scatterplots.</li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </blockquote>
                </div>
            </html>
        </panel>
    </row>
</dashboard>